<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-12T13:01:52+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ideas &amp;amp; Projects | Matteo Pariset</title><subtitle>A nice collection of some of my ideas and projects</subtitle><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><entry><title type="html">SuperGLUE Benchmark</title><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/superglue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SuperGLUE Benchmark" /><published>2020-05-08T18:19:19+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T18:19:19+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/superglue</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://matteopariset.github.io/superglue/">&lt;p&gt;2020.05.08 - I am proud to announce that Infosys iCETS is now in the global &lt;strong&gt;top 10 list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://super.gluebenchmark.com&quot;&gt;SuperGLUE benchmark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a Natural Language Processing benchmark for Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This remarkable achievement was made possible by several months of work and a &lt;strong&gt;team of passionate people&lt;/strong&gt;, I am honored to be part of. An exciting journey, started during my 2019 InStep Internship, has brought me this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank my teammates Sakthi Ganesh M and Dev Sharma for the distance traveled together and all the other Infoscions who believed in this project and have relentlessly provided their guidance and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/SuperGLUE_Leaderboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;SuperGLUE leaderboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><category term="AI" /><category term="NLP" /><category term="SuperGLUE Benchmark" /><summary type="html">2020.05.08 - I am proud to announce that Infosys iCETS is now in the global top 10 list of SuperGLUE benchmark, a Natural Language Processing benchmark for Artificial Intelligence. This remarkable achievement was made possible by several months of work and a team of passionate people, I am honored to be part of. An exciting journey, started during my 2019 InStep Internship, has brought me this far. I would like to thank my teammates Sakthi Ganesh M and Dev Sharma for the distance traveled together and all the other Infoscions who believed in this project and have relentlessly provided their guidance and support.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Update Separator</title><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/update-separator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update Separator" /><published>2020-05-07T18:19:19+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T18:19:19+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/update-separator</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://matteopariset.github.io/update-separator/"></content><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><category term="AI" /><category term="Neural Networks" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Against Fake News / part 1</title><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/fake-news-pt1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Against Fake News / part 1" /><published>2020-05-02T18:19:19+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-02T18:19:19+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/fake-news-pt1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://matteopariset.github.io/fake-news-pt1/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-war-against-fake-news-who-will-win&quot;&gt;The War Against Fake News: Who Will Win?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 World Press Freedom Day comes at an incredibly special time. Today, more than ever before, we feel the urge to advocate for higher-quality information on the Internet. Hundreds of people died in Iran after drinking Methanol, which they believed could fight Coronavirus. A staggering number of human beings are performing the craziest actions, in hope to repel our invisible enemy. Blinded by fear, they are &lt;strong&gt;all preys of misleading rumors&lt;/strong&gt; and blatantly false claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This health emergency has already prompted many popular social media platforms to filter false content and redirect their users to official sources. Facebook alone says than it has redirected more than 100 million users in March. Even though those actions are temporarily slowing down the diffusion of fake news, we are still far from winning the war against misinformation. False knowledge which is - physically - harming people now was cultivated over a longer period of time and is the product of well-organized communities that efficiently spread it. It is amplified by echo chambers, ranging from family WhatsApp groups to anti-vaxxers’ Facebook pages, and propagates &lt;em&gt;more easily than&lt;/em&gt; Covid-19, according to WHO’s director, Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus. Two months ago, he announced that &lt;em&gt;we are not just fighting a pandemic; we are fighting an &lt;strong&gt;infodemic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The war against fake news started many years ago and, when Covid-19 is over (yes, despite appearances, one day that will happen), the infodemic will stay. The time has come to properly acknowledge its existence and think about how &lt;strong&gt;technology can end it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;act-1-why-it-all-began&quot;&gt;Act 1: Why it all began&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before talking about the innovations that could stop the &lt;em&gt;infodemic&lt;/em&gt;, we should look at its beginning. Fake news has been around since we invented writing, but its impact has massively increased over the last two decades. That’s mainly due to the birth of Internet, which represented a new, highly efficient propagation medium for bogus claims. People could communicate with an unprecedented easiness, barbecue lovers as well as conspiracy theorists could effortlessly create and grow their respective virtual communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faced with this epochal change in the way contents were generated, the news industry has struggled to keep up. While other industries underwent major transformations to embrace the &lt;em&gt;digital revolution&lt;/em&gt;, the news market followed a diﬀerent path. It stayed non-digital till recent times and still lacks innovations that couldbring it into the digital world. A clear example is given by online newspapers, which are mostly &lt;strong&gt;old-style newspapers&lt;/strong&gt;, just delivered on your screen. These outdated tools cannot keep the pace of research in AI-driven content production, which has made increasingly harder to ensure photos and videos are authentic. After watching the video below, a distracted user could swear to have seen former US President Barack Obama delivering this unusual speech. Well, that speech was instead pronounced by Jordan Peele.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 25px; height: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cQ54GDm1eL0?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More time and resources are required today to verify contents since those can be cheaply faked using the right softwares. Technology and, with it, the world around us evolve rapidly and journalists need to further specialize to be knowledgeable enough to write accurate articles. Instead, the loss of profits from the sale of paper copies has &lt;strong&gt;bankrupted many newspapers&lt;/strong&gt;, and forced others to &lt;strong&gt;drastically reduce their workforce&lt;/strong&gt;. As The Guardian put it, we have probably entered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2017/apr/15/journalism-faces-a-crisis-worldwide-we-might-be-entering-a-new-dark-age&quot;&gt;Dark Age of journalism&lt;/a&gt;, dominated by a worldwide wave of mergers among ailing publishers. To worsen things, premium plans, required to unlock full access to contents, have redirected casual readers towards lower-quality websites, even more helpless against fake news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;Internet users mostly play a negative role&lt;/strong&gt; in this picture. The two most popular ways of accessing online news, social media and news aggregators, do nothing but accelerating, in their own ways, the decline of journalism. Social networks are purposefully designed to prioritize sensational and popular content and therefore do not work well with news. Multiple researches have shown that false contents, leveraging &lt;strong&gt;anger and fear&lt;/strong&gt;, provoke much stronger emotional reactions than reliable information. Those contents are thus more likely to receive reactions and comments, which are interpreted by recommending algorithms as a sign of their relevance. As to news aggregators, they &lt;strong&gt;unfairly take advantage of the hard work of field reporters&lt;/strong&gt;, by collecting articles from newspapers’ websites without financially supporting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, it should be clear that technology has played a major role in the crisis of journalism and Internet has so far eagerly helped to spread fake news, crafted both by ill-informed bloggers and state-funded criminals.
But, what can technology do to end this crisis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-tuned-up-next-part-2---how-can-technology-help&quot;&gt;Stay tuned! Up next: PART 2 - &lt;strong&gt;How can technology help?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><category term="Fake news" /><category term="Internet" /><category term="Information" /><summary type="html">The War Against Fake News: Who Will Win?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Algorithms</title><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/intro-back-propagation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Algorithms" /><published>2018-08-25T18:19:19+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-25T18:19:19+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/intro-back-propagation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://matteopariset.github.io/intro-back-propagation/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long walk to build a complete artificial brain takes its origin from the most inaccessible questions about existence. It is shaped by the profound meaning we assign to our freedom, our destiny and our soul. It must go through the contradictions of philosophical models of the mind to reach, at last, the insidious land of working prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe artificial intelligence always made men curious precisely because it is far more than an engineering problem. It is an opportunity to gain a deeper insight on this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop of the ambitious journey of AI is the close observation of nature, to reveal and imitate its alchemies. But, in the attempt of using our minds to understand themselves, the ultimate goal of this search comes to light: the reproduction of the noblest expression of intelligence, self-awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will describe some of theory behind the development of this exciting field. In the video below, an example of my AI software recognising letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 25px; height: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/naxejsaj3UU?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Gli esseri umani sono portati a riprodurre per capire e a capire per riprodurre. – &lt;cite&gt;Ernst Mach&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;Next…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;continue-to-read-this-article-online-or-download-the-full-paper-here&quot;&gt;Continue to read this article &lt;a href=&quot;/ai.html&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; or download the full paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://matteopariset.github.io/res/papers/Neural_Networks.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><category term="AI" /><category term="Neural Networks" /><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome</title><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome" /><published>2018-08-09T18:19:19+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-09T18:19:19+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://matteopariset.github.io/welcome/"></content><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LabVIEW Image Composer</title><link href="https://matteopariset.github.io/image-composer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LabVIEW Image Composer" /><published>2018-07-10T18:19:19+02:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T18:19:19+02:00</updated><id>https://matteopariset.github.io/image-composer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://matteopariset.github.io/image-composer/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the &lt;strong&gt;overlap of two &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.jpg&lt;/code&gt; images&lt;/strong&gt; seems pretty simple, it requires some work. To simplify things, below, you can find LabVIEW 2015 code that performs this operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/img-comp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yosh Ginsu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;parameters&quot;&gt;Parameters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Parameter&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;BACK_IMAGE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The path to background image&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;FORE_IMAGE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The path to foreground image&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;WIDTH&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The desired width (in pixels) of the foreground image&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;HEIGHT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The desired height (in pixels) of the foreground image&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;X&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The x-distance (in pixels) of the foreground from the top-left corner of the background&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;INT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The y-distance (in pixels) of the foreground from the top-left corner of the background&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PICTURE_IN&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PICTURE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The picture box displaying the preview&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SAVE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BOOLEAN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;true&lt;/strong&gt; to save the result in the directory of the foreground image as &lt;em&gt;COMBINED.jpg&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;false&lt;/strong&gt; to only display the preview&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;strong&gt;LabVIEW VI&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;/res/soft/ImageComposer.vi&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Matteo Pariset</name></author><category term="LabView" /><category term="VI" /><category term="Image processing" /><summary type="html">Description</summary></entry></feed>